Everybody dies in the end. Drew said as
he tossed a piece of popcorn into
[music] the air. He watched it fall back
down and bounce off his upper lip onto
the apartment floor.
Besides the couch he was sitting on, the
space around and behind him was dark and
almost indiscernible with no lights and
no objects.
What? Kevin said [music] confused
looking over at Drew from the other side
of the couch.
Drew pointed at the TV with the remote
in his hand. On the screen was a
thumbnail of a movie.
At the end of this movie, everybody
dies. It's intense, but it's really
good.
Why would you tell me that? Kevin asked
frustratedly. [music]
I just figured you'd want to know. To,
you know, help decide if you wanted to
watch it or not. [music] It's a super
important part. Yeah, but why would I
want to know that before watching it?
You just ruined it.
Why?
Drew asked [music] earnestly.
What do you mean why?
How does it ruin the movie?
>> [music]
>> You know it's going to end either way.
Hm? Kevin grunted dumbfounded. But it
spoils the ending. Now I know what's
going to happen.
True, Drew said [music] slowing himself
down and taking an audible breath.
But it's too late now. I already [music]
told you. So no point in getting all
upset about it.
Okay, but now I don't want to watch it.
Seriously?
But it's really good. I want to watch
it.
Drew responded.
But you've already seen it.
Yeah, but like I said, it's really good.
I really think you'll like it, too.
And if you enjoy it, will anything
really be spoiled?
Kevin thought to himself for a moment.
Yeah, but I wanted to be able to hope
and theorize and predict what was going
to happen. You know, not know.
If you know essentially everyone dies in
the end, the hope and uncertainty are
gone.
Drew nodded sympathetically.
I've seen it three times.
And every time I watch it, I laugh at
the funny parts, cry at the sad ones,
love and loathe the different
characters, feel the hope and
uncertainty embedded [music] into each
of them, consider all the possible ways
things could go, even if they don't.
I still care.
And the ending doesn't change that.
Both Kevin and Drew paused for a moment,
looking back at the TV screen in
silence.
The movie's thumbnail held in place,
waiting to be started.
Come on, let's watch it. Drew said
matter-of-factly, interrupting the
silence.
Kevin leaned back in the couch cushion,
paused for another moment, and then
grabbed a handful of popcorn.
All right, fine. He said, pointing at
the screen.
Drew lifted up the TV remote and pressed
play.
Various colors and shapes projected onto
Kevin and Drew's faces.
On the screen, a bouquet of lights
shifted and morphed into a family sat at
what seemed to be a kitchen table.
All would not be well in the movie,
but in this moment,
all was well.
>> [music]
>> Thank you so much for watching. One of
the most important things we can do in
life is learn how to better face up to
and embrace the conditions [music]
of our existence.
This, of course, can be extremely
difficult, often convoluted and
overwhelming. But with the right tools,
time, [music] and effort, we can find
better frameworks of perspective and
experience.
I created a guided journal designed to
help make this process more accessible
and engaging. It's called All the Ways
Things Could Go,
>> [music]
>> and it uses creative writing and drawing
prompts to help you explore your
subconscious mind, clarify [music] what
you value, and arrive at deeper, more
honest understandings of yourself and
the world. It's especially helpful for
those who have tried or wanted to
journal, but found it difficult to
[music] know where to start and what to
write about. It's available as both a
hard cover and digital download. If
you're interested, the link is in the
description below.
And of course, as always, thank you so
much for watching in general, and see
you next video.
>> Mhm.